what we have here is called a boolean value. Now note that
python is a case sensitive language, so it's sensitive to lower case and
upper case letters. In this case, if I use a lower case f,
you can see an error over here, because this is not
recognized in python. So false with a capital F
is a special keyword in python that represents the boolean false value.
So this is how we can declare and use variables in python.
Alright, now here's a little exercise for you. Imagine you want to write
a program for a hospital. So we're going to check in a patient named John Smith,
he's 20 years old and is a new patient. I want you to declare
a few variables to store these values. Use the comment box below
to share your code with others.
In this tutorial, I'm going to show you how to receive input from the user.
So in python we have another built in function called input,
we use this to read a value from the terminal window. Let me show you. So
we add parenthesis, then we type a string, here we can type
a message like what is your name. We add a question
mark followed by a space. You will see why we need this space in a second.
So, let's run this program, we get this message,
now we have to enter a value. So we click over here,
now you can see that the caret is separated from the question mark, this is because
of the white space that we added over here. So now we have to type
a value, let's say John, let me press enter,
this function will return the value that we entered in the terminal window.
So we can get that value and store it in a variable.
So, let's declare a variable called name, and set it to the return
value of the input function. Now we can print a greeting message
for this user. So, we use the print function,
we say hello, we add a space, now
after this string, we want to add the value of the name variable. So,
use a plus sign and then type name. What we are doing here
is called string concatenation. So we're combining this string
with another string. Now let's run our program and see what happens.
So what is your name, mosh, now
we get this message, hello mosh. So this is how we can use the
input function in python.
You'll learn about the three types of data in python. We have numbers,
strings, and booleans. Now there are times you want to convert
the value of a variable from one type to another. Let me show you.
So, we're going to use our input function to read the user's
birth year. So enter your birth year.
Now this input function is going to return a value,
so we can store it in a variable called birth underline
year. Okay, now let's write code to calculate
the age of this user. So, we write an expression like this.
Currently we are in the year 2020, so 2020 minus
birth year, this expression or piece of code is going to produce
a value, so once again we can store that value in a variable.
Let's call that variable age. Now let's print age
on the terminal. Let's run our program and see what happens.
So, my birth year is 1982,
enter, oops, our program crashed. So whenever you see this
red message, that indicates an error, so this error occurred
in this file, that is our app.py on line 2.
Right below that you can see the piece of code that
generated this error. So that is this expression, 2020 minus
birth year. Now below that you can see the type of error, so here
we have unsupported types or subtraction.
We have int and str.
What are these? Well this int is short for integer and that represents
a whole number in programming. So, 2020
is an example of an integer. Now birth year
is an example of a string, because whenever we call the input function
this function will return a value as a string. Even if we enter
a number, in other words, when I entered 1982,
this input function returned a string with these characters.
1982. So this string is different from the number
1982. They're completely different types. So in this case,
let me delete these lines, the reason we got this error
is that we tried to subtract a string from an integer.
So our code looked like this, 1982.
Now python doesn't know how to subtract a string from an integer.
So, to solve this problem, we need to convert this string to an